Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're bringing you a great office lesson.
今天我们给你们带来一堂很棒的办公室课程。
That's right, but actually I hope this situation never happens to any of our listeners.
没错，但实际上我希望这种情况永远不会发生在我们的任何听众身上。
Exactly.
确实。
Today we are firing somebody.
今天我们要解雇一个人。
Yikes.
哎呀。
It is a little bit complicated, but maybe you're an HR manager, maybe you are a supervisor,
这有点复杂，但也许你是人力资源经理，也许你是主管，
and you'll have to do this one day.
总有一天你不得不这么做。
So got to learn how, right?
所以得学会怎么做，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好了。
Let's get started then as we listen to Isabel and Anthony.
那我们开始吧，听听Isabel和Anthony的对话。
Hi Isabel.
嗨，Isabel。
You wanted to see me?
你想见我？
Yes, Anthony.
是的，Anthony。
Come on in and have a seat.
进来坐下吧。
Is everything okay?
一切都还好吗？
You seem a bit preoccupied.
你看起来有点心事重重。
Well, Anthony, this is not going to be an easy conversation.
嗯，Anthony，这不会是一次轻松的谈话。
The company has made some decisions which will have a direct impact on your employment.
公司做出了一些决定，这些决定将直接影响你的工作。
Okay.
好吧。
I don't want to beat around the bush, so I'm just going to come out with it.
我不想拐弯抹角，所以我就直说了。
We're going to have to let you go.
我们得让你走了。
What?
什么？
Why?
为什么？
I mean, just like that?
我是说，就这样？
I'm fired?
我被解雇了？
I'm sorry, but to be honest, you're a terrible employee.
我很抱歉，但老实说，你是个糟糕的员工。
What?
什么？
I resent that.
我对此感到不满。
Anthony, you were caught making international calls from the office phone.
Anthony，你被抓到用办公室电话打国际长途。
You called in sick eight times this month, and you smell like alcohol.
你这个月请了八次病假，而且你身上有酒味。
He did sound a little bit like he had too much to drink.
他听起来确实有点像喝多了。
I know.
我知道。
He had that kind of-
他那种——
Slur.
含糊不清的说话方式。
Yeah.
是啊。
That slow way of talking that made him seem a little bit drunk.
那种慢吞吞的说话方式让他看起来有点醉。
Well, that's definitely something you don't want to do is show up to work with alcohol
嗯，你绝对不想做的事情就是带着酒气来上班。
in your breath.
嘴里有酒味。
Exactly.
没错。
But you know what?
但你知道吗？
There's a lot of great language in this dialogue, so why don't we take a look at it now in Language
这段对话里有很多很棒的语言，所以我们不如现在在“语言要点”里看看。
Takeaway.
语言要点。
Language Takeaway.
All right.
好的。
Well, I want to look at three words here.
嗯，我想看三个词。
Now, the first one, Anthony said that Isabel was preoccupied.
第一个，Anthony说Isabel是preoccupied（心事重重）。
Preoccupied.
Preoccupied。
Okay.
好的。
So, if somebody is preoccupied-
所以，如果有人preoccupied——
They're not focused.
他们不专注。
Maybe they're a little bit worried.
也许他们有点担心。
Yeah, they're thinking of something else.
是的，他们在想别的事情。
Okay.
好的。
Why don't we take a listen to a few examples of how this word is used?
我们不如听几个例子，看看这个词怎么用？
Example one.
例子一。
James is really preoccupied.
James真的很心事重重。
I think he's having some family problems.
我想他家里出了点问题。
Example two.
例子二。
Oh, were you talking to me, honey?
哦，你在跟我说话吗，亲爱的？
I'm sorry.
对不起。
I'm just really preoccupied with work.
我只是太专注于工作了。
All right.
好的。
So, very clear now.
所以，现在很清楚了。
Preoccupied.
Preoccupied。
Let's move on to our next word.
我们继续看下一个词。
Direct impact.
Direct impact（直接影响）。
Direct impact。
A direct impact.
一个直接影响。
All right.
好的。
So, again, Isabel told Anthony that the decision will have a direct impact on his career.
所以，再次，Isabel告诉Anthony这个决定会直接影响他的职业生涯。
It will have a noticeable or impact or effect on his career.
这会对他的职业生涯产生明显的影响或效果。
Okay.
好的。
So, a direct impact.
所以，direct impact。
And what about our last word?
那我们的最后一个词呢？
Well, Anthony said, I resent that.
嗯，Anthony说，I resent that（我对此感到不满）。
Resent.
Resent。
Okay.
好的。
Now, this is spelled exactly like resent, like with an S, right?
现在，这个词的拼写和resent一样，带S，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
R-E-S-E-N-T.
R-E-S-E-N-T。
But you pronounce it like a Z.
但发音像Z。
Resent.
Resent。
Resent that.
Resent that。
So, what does it mean if you say, I resent that?
所以，如果你说I resent that，是什么意思？
It means, I find that insulting.
意思是，我觉得那很冒犯。
I find that to be not true.
我觉得那不是真的。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
All right, Marco.
好了，Marco。
Well, how do you use this word?
嗯，你怎么用这个词？
Well, if somebody tells you, you're lazy.
嗯，如果有人告诉你，你很懒。
Okay.
好的。
Right.
对。
Then you might say, hey, I resent that.
那你可能会说，嘿，我对此感到不满。
Right.
对。
I do a lot of work.
我做了很多工作。
I'm not lazy.
我不懒。
Yeah.
是啊。
So, it's always something that you use after someone insults you.
所以，这总是用在别人侮辱你之后。
Right.
对。
Or says something that you find to be not true.
或者说了你觉得不真实的话。
Okay.
好的。
Resent that.
Resent that。
And I guess with this, it's time for us to listen to this dialogue again, and then we'll
我想说到这里，是时候再听一遍这段对话了，然后我们会回来看看一些很棒的短语。
come back and look at some great phrases.
然后我们会回来看看一些很棒的短语。
Hi, Isabel.
嗨，Isabel。
You wanted to see me?
你想见我？
Yes, Anthony.
是的，Anthony。
Come on in and have a seat.
进来坐下吧。
Is everything okay?
一切都还好吗？
You seem a bit preoccupied.
你看起来有点心事重重。
Well, Anthony, this is not going to be an easy conversation.
嗯，Anthony，这不会是一次轻松的谈话。
The company has made some decisions which will have a direct impact on your employment.
公司做出了一些决定，这些决定将直接影响你的工作。
Okay.
好吧。
I don't want to beat around the bush, so I'm just going to come out with it.
我不想拐弯抹角，所以我就直说了。
We're going to have to let you go.
我们得让你走了。
What?
什么？
Why?
为什么？
I mean, just like that?
我是说，就这样？
I'm fired?
我被解雇了？
I'm sorry, but to be honest, you're a terrible employee.
我很抱歉，但老实说，你是个糟糕的员工。
What?
什么？
I resent that.
我对此感到不满。
Anthony, you were caught making international calls from the office phone.
Anthony，你被抓到用办公室电话打国际长途。
You called in sick eight times this month, and you smell like alcohol.
你这个月请了八次病假，而且你身上有酒味。
Yeah, well, there's some wonderful language in here that you can use when you have to
是啊，嗯，这里面有一些很棒的语言，当你不得不和别人进行困难的谈话时可以用。
have a difficult conversation with somebody.
当你不得不和别人进行困难的谈话时可以用。
Right.
对。
So, let's take a look at these phrases in Fluency Builder.
所以，让我们在“流利度构建”中看看这些短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
We have three phrases here, and the first one is to beat around the bush.
我们这里有三个短语，第一个是to beat around the bush（拐弯抹角）。
Okay.
好的。
Beat around the bush.
Beat around the bush。
Okay.
好的。
So, this is an idiomatic phrase.
所以，这是一个习语短语。
So, before we explain it, let's listen to somebody beating around the bush.
所以，在我们解释之前，让我们听听有人拐弯抹角。
Okay.
好的。
The one thing that I want to tell you, it's so important that I don't like.
我想告诉你的一件事，它很重要，我不喜欢。
I always, sometimes when, all right, here's the deal.
我总是，有时候，好吧，事情是这样的。
This is it.
就是这个。
It's not me.
不是我。
It's not this.
不是这个。
It's not that.
不是那个。
It's not you.
不是你。
It's not me.
不是我。
It's everyone.
是每个人。
It's everything.
是一切。
Do you understand what I'm saying?
你明白我在说什么吗？
So, as you can tell, the person has something to say, but they're taking a long time to
所以，正如你所看到的，这个人有话要说，但他们花了很长时间才说出来。
say it.
对。
Right.
你是在找合适的或者更礼貌的词来说某事。
You're kind of looking for the right or maybe more polite words to say something.
没错。
Exactly.
所以，那就是to beat around the bush。
So, that is to beat around the bush.
现在，to beat around the bush的反义词是to come out with it（直说出来）。
Now, the opposite of to beat around the bush is to come out with it.
好的。
Okay.
Come out with it。
Come out with it.
所以，也许你在和你的朋友说话，他在拐弯抹角，所以你可以直接说，嘿，直说吧。
So, maybe you're talking to your friend and he's beating around the bush, so you can just
告诉我。
say, hey, come out with it.
Tell me.
到底是什么？
没错。
Just what is it?
对。
Exactly.
Come out with it。
Right.
直接点。
Come out with it.
当Isabel终于直说出来时，她告诉Anthony我们得让你走了。
Be direct.
Let you go（让你走）。
When Isabel finally came out with it, she told Anthony that we're going to have to
Let you go。
let you go.
所以，这实际上是说你被解雇的一种更委婉的方式。
Let you go.
是啊。
这更礼貌一点，不是吗？
So, this is actually a nicer way of saying you're fired.
对。
Yeah.
就是，我们得让你走了或者……
It's a little bit more polite, isn't it?
哦，我被公司解雇了。
Right.
对。
It's, we're going to have to let you go or...
所以，to be fired的同义词。
Oh, I was let go from my company.
没错。
Right.
好的。
So, the synonym for to be fired.
所以，让我们再听一遍Anthony被解雇，然后我们会回来多谈谈这个困难的情况。
Exactly.
然后我们会回来多谈谈这个困难的情况。
Okay.
嗨，Isabel。
So, let's listen to Anthony getting fired one more time and then we'll come back and
你想见我？
talk a little bit more about this difficult situation.
是的，Anthony。
Hi, Isabel.
进来坐下吧。
You wanted to see me?
一切都还好吗？
Yes, Anthony.
你看起来有点心事重重。
Come on in and have a seat.
嗯，Anthony，这不会是一次轻松的谈话。
Is everything okay?
公司做出了一些决定，这些决定将直接影响你的工作。
You seem a bit preoccupied.
好吧。
Well, Anthony, this is not going to be an easy conversation.
我不想拐弯抹角，所以我就直说了。
The company has made some decisions which will have a direct impact on your employment.
我们得让你走了。
Okay.
什么？
I don't want to beat around the bush, so I'm just going to come out with it.
为什么？
We're going to have to let you go.
我是说，就这样？
What?
什么？
Why?
为什么？
I mean, just like that?
我是说，就这样？
I'm fired?
我被解雇了？
I'm sorry, but to be honest, you're a terrible employee.
抱歉，但说实话，你是个糟糕的员工。
What?
什么？
I resent that.
我对此感到不满。
Anthony, you were caught making international calls from the office phone.
安东尼，你被抓到用办公室电话打国际长途。
You called in sick eight times this month and you smell like alcohol.
你这个月请了八次病假，而且身上还有酒味。
So, Erica, have you ever fired anyone?
那么，埃里卡，你解雇过别人吗？
I have fired a lot of people.
我解雇过很多人。
Wow.
哇。
You are a mean person.
你是个刻薄的人。
Oh, yeah.
哦，是啊。
Well, you know, there are some people who really do silly things like come to work drunk.
嗯，你知道，有些人确实会做傻事，比如喝醉了来上班。
And if you do that, you're obviously going to get fired.
如果你那样做，显然会被解雇。
But in the United States, actually, there is an interesting way of firing people.
但在美国，实际上有一种有趣的解雇方式。
They get a pink slip.
他们会收到一张粉红单。
Oh, yeah.
哦，是啊。
But I guess this is just a little bit different than getting fired.
但我想这和直接被解雇有点不同。
You get a pink slip when you get laid off.
当你被裁员时会收到粉红单。
Right.
对。
I mean, if you come to work drunk, you get fired immediately, right?
我是说，如果你喝醉了来上班，你会立刻被解雇，对吧？
But when you get a pink slip, so it's basically a little pink paper that tells you that you
但当你收到粉红单时，它基本上是一张粉红色的小纸条，告诉你
have been laid off.
你被裁员了。
Yeah.
嗯。
And so when you hear somebody say we sent out.
所以当你听到有人说我们发出了……
Yeah.
嗯。
So when you hear somebody talk about pink slips, like we send like our company sent
所以当你听到有人谈论粉红单，比如我们公司发出了
out 500 pink slips, you know, that means that 500 people got laid off or I got a pink slip
500张粉红单，你知道，那意味着500人被裁员了，或者我今天收到了一张粉红单
today.
今天。
That means you got laid off.
那意味着你被裁员了。
Right.
对。
Yeah.
嗯。
That's actually interesting because I don't know any other country that actually has this
这其实挺有意思的，因为我不知道还有哪个国家有这种
of special color, special color for firing people.
特殊的颜色，专门用来解雇人。
Yeah.
嗯。
How about in your country?
你们国家呢？
Is there a special color for pink slips?
有特殊的颜色代表粉红单吗？
If you guys have any stories as well, maybe about being fired or maybe you've had to fire
如果你们也有故事，也许关于被解雇，或者你不得不解雇
somebody.
别人。
Come to our website and tell us about it.
来我们的网站告诉我们吧。
Right.
对。
EnglishPod.com.
EnglishPod.com。
There you can leave your questions and comments.
在那里你可以留下你的问题和评论。
Erika and I are always there trying to answer your questions and also our great community
埃里卡和我总是在那里努力回答你们的问题，还有我们很棒的社区
is there.
也在那里。
They will also help.
他们也会帮忙。
Okay, guys.
好了，各位。
Well, we're out of time for today.
嗯，我们今天的时间到了。
But until next time.
但下次再见。
Bye.
再见。